<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>THALIUM</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on THALIUM</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2020, all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join Us</title><link>/joinus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/joinus/</guid><description>Offres Thalium Dans le cadre de nos travaux R&amp;amp;D ou pour nos besoins clients, l&amp;rsquo;équipe Thalium développe son expertise autour des domaines suivants :
Recherche et exploitation de vulnérabilités Fuzzing Développements kernel / userland Connaissance de la menace et investigation numérique Et ce sur de multiples plateformes :
Windows, Linux, macOS Android, iOS, IOT Intel, ARM Pour répondre aux challenges de plus en plus nombreux, nous recherchons continuellement de nouveaux experts pour nos équipes Reverse, Développements ou encore Forensics.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Au sein du groupe THALES, l&amp;rsquo;équipe THALIUM - basée à Rennes - est dédiée aux activités de Lutte Informatique, de connaissance de la menace, de recherche de vulnérabilités et de développement d’outils de type Red Team.
Nous recrutons !!
Thalium, part of THALES group, is focused on threat intelligence, vulnerability research and red team development.</description></item><item><title>Leveraging Android Permissions: A Solver Approach</title><link>/posts/leveraging-android-permissions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leveraging-android-permissions/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Android permission management system has already suffered from several vulnerabilities in the past. Such weaknesses can grant dangerous permissions to a malevolent application, an example being &lt;code>CALL_LOG&lt;/code>, which gives access to all incoming and outgoing calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post dives into the Android permission system and how a solver was leveraged to find new vulnerabilities. With this approach, a privilege escalation was identified, which was fixed and assigned CVE-2023-20947 by Google.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>kSMBd: a quick overview</title><link>/posts/ksmbd-trailer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ksmbd-trailer/</guid><description>In this blogpost, we introduce the analysis of one SMB implementation: kSMBd. It will be followed up by a talk at OffensiveCon 2023 named &amp;ldquo;Abusing Linux in-kernel SMB server to gain kernel remote code execution&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Fuzzing Guide to the Galaxy: An Attempt with Android System Services</title><link>/posts/fuzzing-samsung-system-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fuzzing-samsung-system-services/</guid><description>Although the Android base is open source, many different constructors customize it with their own UIs and APIs. All these additions represent an extra attack surface that can change from one phone model to another. We tried to automatically fuzz the closed-source system services powering these modifications, discovering &lt;code>CVE-2022-39907&lt;/code> and &lt;code>CVE-2022-39908&lt;/code> along the way.</description></item><item><title>ARM TrustZone: pivoting to the secure world</title><link>/posts/pivoting_to_the_secure_world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pivoting_to_the_secure_world/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Discovery of two vulnerabilities in secure world components&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exploitation to get code execution in a trusted driver, while not having a debugger for this obscure environment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leverage of aarch32 T32 instruction set to find nice stack pivots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turning an arbitrary write into an arbitrary code execution&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Fuzzing RDPEGFX with "what the fuzz"</title><link>/posts/rdpegfx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/rdpegfx/</guid><description>Microsoft’s Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP) client was fuzzed by various teams in the past few years, it thus seemed like a good target to try a recent snapshot fuzzer: &lt;a href="https://github.com/0vercl0k/wtf">what the fuzz (wtf)&lt;/a> (of which we are only users). In this companion post to our &lt;a href="https://www.hexacon.fr/conference/speakers/#fuzzing_rdpegfx">Hexacon 2022 talk&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="/posts/misc/rdpegfx/Hexacon2022-Fuzzing_RDPEGFX_with_wtf.pdf">slides&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/4pftjmKqeoM">video&lt;/a>) we’ll show how we took advantage of wtf flexibility in order to efficiently fuzz the RDPEGFX channel of Microsoft RDP client and uncover &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2022-30221">CVE-2022-30221&lt;/a>.</description></item><item><title>Remote Deserialization Bug in Microsoft's RDP Client through Smart Card Extension (CVE-2021-38666)</title><link>/posts/deserialization-bug-through-rdp-smart-card-extension/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 06:00:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/deserialization-bug-through-rdp-smart-card-extension/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the &lt;strong>third installment&lt;/strong> in my three-part series of articles on fuzzing Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s RDP client, where I explain a bug I found by fuzzing the &lt;strong>smart card extension&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remote ASLR Leak in Microsoft's RDP Client through Printer Cache Registry (CVE-2021-38665)</title><link>/posts/leaking-aslr-through-rdp-printer-cache-registry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/leaking-aslr-through-rdp-printer-cache-registry/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the &lt;strong>second installment&lt;/strong> in my three-part series of articles on fuzzing Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s RDP client. I will explain a bug I found by fuzzing the &lt;strong>printer sub-protocol&lt;/strong>, and how I exploited it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fuzzing Microsoft's RDP Client using Virtual Channels: Overview &amp; Methodology</title><link>/posts/fuzzing-microsoft-rdp-client-using-virtual-channels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fuzzing-microsoft-rdp-client-using-virtual-channels/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article begins my three-part series on fuzzing Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s RDP client. In this &lt;strong>first installment&lt;/strong>, I set up a methodology for &lt;strong>fuzzing Virtual Channels&lt;/strong> using WinAFL and share some of my findings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ECW 2021 - WriteUp</title><link>/posts/ecw2021-writeup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 12:00:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/ecw2021-writeup/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the &lt;a href="https://www.european-cyber-week.eu/">European Cyber Week&lt;/a> CTF 2021 Thalium created some challenges in our core competencies: reverse and exploitation. This blog post presents some of the write-ups:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#chest">Chest (36 solve) - reverse&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#fsb-as-a-service">FSB as a service (3 solve) - exploitation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#wysiwyg">WYSIWYG (3 solve) - reverse&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pipe Dream (1 solve) - reverse
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the author posted his solution on &lt;a href="https://face.0xff.re/posts/ecw-ctf-2021-pipe-dream-writeup/">his personal blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Thalium&amp;rsquo;s challenges have been less resolved than others. They were not that difficult, but probably a bit more unexpected. A few additional challenges designed by Thalium are:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NT objects access tracing</title><link>/posts/nt_py_icebox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/nt_py_icebox/</guid><description>Draw me a map As homework during the lockdown, I wanted to automate the attack surface analysis of a target on Windows. The main objective was to construct a view of a software architecture to highlight the attack surface (whether remote or local).
The software architecture can be composed of several elements:
processes privileges ipc etc Usually, software architecture analysis is done with tools that give a view at a specific time (ProcessHacker, WinObjEx, etc).</description></item><item><title>SSTIC : how to setup a ctf win10 pwn user environment</title><link>/posts/sstic_infra_windows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/sstic_infra_windows/</guid><description>Introduction This post aims to present how to easily setup a lightweight secure user pwning environment for Windows. From your binary challenge communicating with stdin/stdout, this environment provides a multi-client broker listening on a socket, redirecting it to the IO of your binary, and executing it in a jail. This environment is mainly based on the project AppJaillauncher-rs from trailofbits, with some security fixes and some tips to easily setup the RW rights to the system files from the jail.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Apocalypse 2021 5/5 - Artillery</title><link>/posts/apocalypse2021-artillery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 12:00:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/apocalypse2021-artillery/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artillery&lt;/strong> was a web challenge of the Cyber Apocalypse 2021 CTF organized by HackTheBox. We were given the source code of the server to help us solve the challenge. This challenge was a nice opportunity to learn more about &lt;strong>XXE&lt;/strong> vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyber Apocalypse 2021 4/5 - Discovery</title><link>/posts/apocalypse2021-discovery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 12:00:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/apocalypse2021-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the least solved challenges, yet probably not the most difficult one. It is a Hardware challenge, though it is significantly different from the other challenges of this category. The first thing to spot is that when starting the challenge machine, we have access to two network services:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>an HTTP server, requesting an authentication&lt;/li>
&lt;li>an AMQP broker, &lt;code>rabbitmq&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Cyber Apocalypse 2021 3/5 - Off the grid</title><link>/posts/apocalypse2021-off-the-grid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 12:00:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/apocalypse2021-off-the-grid/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Off-the-grid&lt;/strong> was the 4th hardware challenge of the Cyber Apocalypse 2021 CTF organized by HackTheBox.
We were given an &lt;a href="/posts/misc/off-the-grid/off_the_grid.sal">Saleae trace&lt;/a> and schematics to analyse. Thalium was one of the very first of 99 players to complete it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyber Apocalypse 2021 2/5 - Wii-Phit</title><link>/posts/apocalypse2021-wii-phit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 12:00:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/apocalypse2021-wii-phit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wii-Phit&lt;/strong> was the only &lt;em>Hard&lt;/em> crypto challenge designed by &lt;a href="https://cryptohack.org/">CryptoHack&lt;/a> for the &lt;a href="https://www.hackthebox.eu/cyber-apocalypse-ctf-2021">Cyber Apocalypse 2021&lt;/a> CTF (there were also 4 challenges categorized as &lt;em>Insane&lt;/em> though).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is already an excellent &lt;a href="https://blog.cryptohack.org/cyber-apocalypse-2021#wii-phit">writeup&lt;/a> by the challenge organizers:
one could recognize a well known equation related to the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erd%C5%91s%E2%80%93Straus_conjecture">Erdős–Straus conjecture&lt;/a>, some participants used &lt;a href="https://github.com/Z3Prover/z3">Z3&lt;/a>.
We took a different approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyber Apocalypse 2021 1/5 - PWN challenges</title><link>/posts/apocalypse2021-pwn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/apocalypse2021-pwn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thalium participated in the &lt;a href="https://www.hackthebox.eu/cyber-apocalypse-ctf-2021">Cyber Apocalypse 2021&lt;/a> CTF organized last week by &lt;a href="https://www.hackthebox.eu/">HackTheBox&lt;/a>.
It was a great success with 4,740 teams composed of around 10,000 hackers from all over the world.
Our team finished in fifth place and solved sixty out of the sixty-two challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="/posts/img/Cyber_Apocalypse_2021-scoreboard.png" target="_blank">
&lt;img src="/posts/img/Cyber_Apocalypse_2021-scoreboard.png" alt="fig_scoreboard">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article explains how we solved each pwn challenge and what tools we used, it is written to be accessible to beginners:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows Memory Introspection with IceBox</title><link>/posts/windows-full-memory-introspection-with-icebox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/windows-full-memory-introspection-with-icebox/</guid><description>Virtual Machine Introspection (VMI) is an extremely powerful technique to explore a guest OS. Directly acting on the hypervisor allows a stealth and precise control of the guest state, which means its CPU context as well as its memory.
Basically, a common use case in VMI consists in (1) setting a breakpoint on an address, (2) wait for a break and (3) finally read some virtual memory. For example, to simply monitor the user file writing activity on Windows, just set a breakpoint on the NtWriteFile function in kernel land.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Icebox VMI</title><link>/posts/getting_started/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/getting_started/</guid><description>Icebox is a VMI (Virtual Machine Introspection) framework enabling you to stealthily trace and debug any kernel or user code system-wide.
All Icebox source code can be found on our github page.
Try Icebox Icebox now comes with full Python bindings enabling fast prototyping on top of VMI, whether you want to trace a user process or inspect the kernel internals.
The core itself is in C++ and exposes most of its public functions into an icebox Python 3 module.</description></item></channel></rss>